A Finding Aid to the Hiram Powers Papers, 1819-1953, bulk 1835-1883, in the Archives of American Art AAA.powehira
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1819-1883; Series 2; (Box 1-10; 9.0 linear feet)
  - P, Miscellaneous: Ph-Po, 1846-1872 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    Pochain, George W.
    Polhemus, A.
    Polidori, Fratelli
    Porcinai, Pasquale
    Porter, F. G.
    Poole, Theresa
    Potter, Edmund
  - P, Miscellaneous: Pra-Pri, 1838-1877 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    Pratt, William A.
    Prentice, John H.
    Preston, Mrs. William H.
    Price, Eli K.
    Price, Mary Mulock
    Price, Stephen
    Prime, Rufus
    Prime, S. Irenaus[?]
    Pritchard, Arthur J.
    Pritchard, Richard O.
  - P, Miscellaneous: Pro-Pu, 1854-1870 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    Probasco, Henry
    Pugh, G. E.
    Pugh, Isaac
    Putnam, C.
  - Ray, Mary, 1853-1859 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Reilly, Benjamin T., 1837, 1855-1866; (6 folders) (Box 8, Folder 31-36)
  - Reilly, Boyd, 1849-1855; (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 37-39)
  - Richardson, John P., 1853-1866; (6 folders) (Box 8, Folder 40-45)
  - Robb, James, 1845-1848 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Russell, G. R., 1862-1864 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Rymer, Wilkie & Emma, circa 1856-1858 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - R, Miscellaneous: Ra-Re, 1843-1873 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    Ralston, Lizzie H.
    Rankin, Isaac N.
    Raymond, Mary A.
    Raymond, R. R.
    Raywood, Marian
    Reaman, G. H.
    Reeves, Samuel J.
    Revoil, B. H.
    Reynold, William
  - R, Miscellaneous: Ric, 1853-1873 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    Rice, Clinton
    Rice, Peter
    Rice, Thomas G.
    Rice, William T.
    Rice Rutter & Co.
    Richards, Samuel
    Richardson, Jason
    Richmond, George
    Richmond, Julia
  - R, Miscellaneous: Rid-Riv, 1851-1865 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    Riddick, Washington
    Ridley, G.
    Ridpath, James
    Ridpath, Samuel
    Riggs, George S.
    Rinehart, William H.
    Ripley, John S.
    Rives, W. C.
  - R, Miscellaneous: Rob-Rog, 1857-1873 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    Robertson, D. A.
    Robertson, John
    Robinson, Chase & Co.
    Rocchi, Mr.
    Rogers, John
    Rogers, Randolph
  - R, Miscellaneous: Rop-Rou, 1854-1871 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    Ropes, Joseph
    Rose, James
    Rothermel, P. F.
    Rothery, Mary A. Hume
    Rothschild, A.
    Routh, Eliza
  - R, Miscellaneous: Ru-Ry, 1846-1866 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    Russell, Mrs. M. B.
    Russell, Georgiana
    Russell, William
    Ryder, W. H.
    Rymer, Jno. T.
  - Salghetti-Drioli, Francesco, 1840-1867 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Sargent, Ignatius, 1849-1869; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 56-57)
  - Saul, James, 1844-1852 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Schurster, F., 1865-1867 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Schwarz, J. G., 1840-1857 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Sigourney, Henry, 1853-1854 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Skottowe, Charles, circa 1845-1852 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Slaughter, Philip, 1850-1856 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Slidell, John, circa 1841-1849 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Smith, C. Lesingham, 1843-1846 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Smyth, Mr., 1850-1855 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Sparks, Jared & Mary, 1855-1867; (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
  - Sprague, Horatio I., 1850-1853 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Spurgin, John, 1853-1866 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Stamer, Caroline (Lady), circa 1842-1853; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
  - Stansbury, Charles F. (Stansbury & Pitman), 1856-1862 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Stanton, Daniel, 1846-1855 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Stewart, Alex T., 1866-1871 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Story, W. W., 1849-1866 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Stoughton, A. B., 1853-1867 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Stoughton, E. W., 1869-1870 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Strong, Charles E., 1860-1862 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Stubs, Joseph, 1842-1858 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Stubs, Mary, 1850-1852 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Stubs, Peter, 1843-1871 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Sturges, B., 1850, 1862-1864 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Surget, F., 1852-1856 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sal-San, 1846-1870 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    Salvestrini, Pasquale
    Samson, George W.
    Sanders, J. Milton
    Sanders, William C.
    Sanderson, J. E.
    Sandford, F. R.
    Sanford, Henry
    Sanford, Joseph
    Sanford, Rollin
    Santavelli, Emilio
    Santini, A. Giusseppe
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sar-Sav, 1838-1869 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    Sard, J. G.
    Sargent, F. W.
    Sargent, L. M.
    Sargent, Manlius[?]
    Sartain, John
    Sartori, John B.
    Saturday Courier
    Savannah Republican
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sc, 1841-1870 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    Schoenberger, John H.
    Scholfield, W. F.
    Schuster, S.
    Schowlgwin[?], Alene
    Scott, Edward H.
    Scott, G. B.
    Scudder, Nannie B.
  - S, Miscellaneous: Se, 1840-1870 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    Seafield, Mr.
    Seaman, John F.
    Sedgwick, Theodore
    Sega, James
    Seibert, Edward
    Seton, W.
    Seward, C. A.
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sh, 1846-1871 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    Shaw, Fran. George
    Shaw, George B.
    Shaw, Gardiner Howland
    Sheldon, Edwin
    Sherman, Mrs. Genl.
    Shields, G. W.
    Shimmin, Charles F.
  - S, Miscellaneous: Si-Sl, 1844-1872 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    Sickles, J. F.
    Silsbee, Nath.
    Skidley, Mr.
    Slaghek, L. Heukensfeldt
    Slater, B. N.
    Sloane, F. I.
    Slocomb, C. H.
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sm-So, 1837-1873 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    Smith, Charles A.
    Smith, Edward C.
    Smith, Jno. Jay
    Smith, Martin T.
    Smith, P. H.
    Smith, Wash. Jackson
    Smith Brothers
    Snell, James Pendleton
    Sohier, William D.
    Southworth, S. S.
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sp-Sq, 1853-1866 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    Spence, Mr.
    Spencer, Earl
    Spencer, H. W.
    Spencer, William B.
    Spring, Marcus
    Squier, Charles
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sta-Ste, 1846-1873 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    Stagg, John
    Stapleford, Edward
    Stanhope, H. Scudamore
    Starbuck, Edward F.
    Stebbins, Emma
    Stephens, Edward B.
    Stephenson, George S.
    Stetson, Mr.
    Stewart, G. H.
    Stewart, Jas. M.
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sti-Sto, 1843-1870 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    Stiglmeier[?], Mr.
    Stiles, William H.
    Stille, C. J.
    Stone, A. B.
    Stone, Dan
    Stone, R. K.
    Stout, Arthur B.
    Stout, A. V.
  - S, Miscellaneous: Str-Sy, 1840-1868 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    Street, Augustus R.
    Street, Julia
    Strong, G. T.
    Strong, J. H.
    Strutt, Arthur J.
    Strutt, Jac. George
    Sturynsky[?], Mr.
    Stuyvesant, N. M.
    Symmes, Joseph
  - Tandy, David C., 1847-1854 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Taylor, James, 1862-1873 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Tegoborski, Mr., 1864-1866 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Terry, Luther, 1841-1858 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Tiffany, O. C., 1847-1851 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Townsend, Isaiah, 1841-1848 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Trollope, Frances & T. Adolphus, 1853-1872 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Tuckerman, Henry, 1846-1866; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 38-39)
  - Tyler, George F., 1866-1867 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - T, Miscellaneous: Ta, 1845-1873 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    Taft, Judge
    Tappan, H. P.
    Taunton, Lord
    Taylor, Mrs. B. Ogle
    Taylor, C. Fred.
    Taylor, George C.
    Taylor, J. Bayard
    Taylor, James
    Taylor, M. S.
    Taylor, P. M.
    Taylor, Rebecca
    Taylor, William
  - T, Miscellaneous: Te, 1852-1856 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    Tefft, T. A.
    Tennyson, F.
    Tetedoux, Clement
  - T, Miscellaneous: Th, 1837-1870 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    Thairlwall[?], R.
    Thalheimer, Miss M E.
    Thatcher, Henry K.
    Thomas, John
    Thomas Loyd & Co.
    Thomas, William L.
    Thompson, C. G.
    Thomson, I.
    Thurston, F. G.
  - T, Miscellaneous: Ti, 1841-1861 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    Tibaldi, J.
    Tiffany, C.
    Tiffany, George Peabody
    Tiffany, Ormond
  - T, Miscellaneous: To, 1840-1864 (Box 9, Folder 45)
    Torrigiani, Carlo
    Tower, Sarabell
    Tower, T.
    Townsend, J. B.
    Townsend, Robert
    Townsend, William H.
    Townshend, Charles
  - T, Miscellaneous: Tr-Tw, 1847-1869 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    Trapier, Paul
    Treat, Joseph
    Trippet, John
    Tweedy, E.
  - Udny, John, 1845-1847 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - U-V Miscellaneous: U-Van, 1841-1866 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    United States Consul, Havre
    Utterson, Edward P.
    Van Buren, A.
    Van Buren, J. T.
    Van Buren, M.
    Vanderbilt, Cornelius
    Vanderlyn, John
    Vanderwoort, Mr.
    Van Rensselaer, C.
    Van Vleet, Miss S. J.
    Van Vleit, Nettie
  - V, Miscellaneous: Var-Vo, 1841-1858 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    Varnum, Joseph B.
    Vernon, Mr.
    Virtue, Frances Adelaide
    Viti, Vito
    Visez, W. H.
    Vorni, Tanto
  - Wadsworth, James S., 1855-1858 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Wales, George W., 1842-1872 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Wales, S. H., 1868-1869 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Warburton, William, 1864-1866 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Ward, Lord, 1848-1849 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Ward, Samuel G. & Anna Barker Ward, 1837-1845; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 55-56)
  - Warren, S. D., 1853-1855 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Watherston, Edward J., 1868 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Weed, Charles A., 1870-1871 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Wetmore, W. T., 1846-1849 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Whilldin, Alexander, 1869-1870 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Wickliffe, R., circa 1844-1847; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 62-63)
  - Williams, G. Stedman, 1870-1871 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Williamson, John & Charlotte Ann, 1866-1868 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Wilson, Dr. W. & Mrs., circa 1854-1878; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 66-67)
  - Winthrop, Robert C., 1841-1871; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 68-69)
  - Wise, Charlotte E., 1853-1869 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Wise, H. A., 1852 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Wolcott, J. Huntington, 1863-1868 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Wolfe, John, 1852-1855 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Woods, Marshall & Mrs., 1852-1870 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Worcester, Thomas, 1850-1870 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wad-Wal, 1840-1861 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Wadsworth, E. A.
    Wales, Thomas B.
    Walker, Joseph
    Wallace & Co.
    Waller, Alb.
    Wallis & Co.
    Walpole, Francis
    Walter, L. M.
    Walton, J. B.
    Walton, W.
  - W, Miscellaneous: War-Wau, 1846-1873 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Ward, John S.
    Ward, Joseph M.
    Ward, Marcus L.
    Ware, William
    Warner, Henderson
    Warren, G. Washington
    Warwick, Mr.
    Waugh, S. B.
    Wautter, Baroness
  - W, Miscellaneous: We, 1836-1869 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Webster, Daniel
    Wedderbury, A.
    Weekes, H.
    Welles & Greene
    Wells, Henry
    Wells, I. E.
    Welman, C. Noel
    Welsch, M. W.
    West, Mary H.
    Westcott, Bayse N.
    Westenholm, George
  - W, Miscellaneous: Whe, 1841-1868 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Wheeler, Charles
    Wheeler, Jno. H.
    Wheelwright, Andrew C.
    Wheelwright, C. H.
  - W, Miscellaneous: Whi, 1847-1873 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Whilldin, L. M.
    Whipple, John A.
    White, Edward B.
    White, Elizabeth G.
    White, Edwin & Harriet
    Whiting, D. P.
    Whiting, William B.
    Whitman, S.
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wig-Wil, 1847-1872 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Wiggins, Charles
    Wilde, John P.
    Wilde, R. H. & Mrs.
    Wiley, L. M.
    Wilkin, Alex
    Wilkinson, John
    Williams, G. P.
    Williams, John S.
    Williams, Virgil
    Willits, Charles C.
    Wilson, Alex G.
    Wilson, John S.
  - W, Miscellaneous: Win-Wit, 1846-1852 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    Winchester, W. T.
    Winthrop, B. R.
    Winthrop, William
    Witmer, Theo. B.
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wo, 1836-1873 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Wolcott, G. H.
    Wolf, Leo.
    Wood, George
    Wood, J. Warrenton
    Woodburn, W.
    Woodbury, Levi
    Woodcock, Charles
    Worcester, E. D.
    Worcester, John Dean
    Worthington, Mrs. Lewis
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wr-Wy, 1848-1870 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Wray, I. M.
    Wright, William S.
    Wurtz, George W.
    Wyatt, M. Digby
    Wynne, R.
  - Young, Jno. J., 1854-1859 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Y-Z, Miscellaneous, 1841-1855 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Yates, A. E.
    Young, Henry
    Zannetti, Professore
  - Unidentified Correspondents, 1849-1868; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 18-19)
  - Unidentified Correspondents, Undated, circa 1840-1873 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Bound Copies of Letters Written by Hiram Powers, 1838-1847; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 21-22)
  - Bound Copies of Letters Written by Hiram Powers, Transcripts, 1838-1847; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 23-24)
  - Envelopes, circa 1860s (Box 10, Folder 25)
- Writings, 1827-1887; Series 3; (Box 10; 0.3 linear feet)
  This series contains writings by Hiram Powers and writings by others. Included here is Powers' "Studio Memorandum," a notebook he kept from 1841 to 1845, which contains dated notations of letters written, receipts and expenditures, business contacts, works in progress, commissions and price quotations for work, comments on problems encountered during studio work, and other notes. Also found are several original poems written by Powers and brief autobiographical writings, such as problems with his eyes and details regarding his arrival in Europe in 1837. Other writings by Powers include an incomplete story titled "Ghost Story," advice for a young sculptor, and directions regarding his sculptures, such as step by step instructions on using tools and directions for handling finished sculptures.
  Writings by others include numerous poems written for Powers, many in praise of one of his sculptures. Of note are a poem by President John Quincy Adams, a poem by Elizabeth Barrett Browning in praise of Powers' "Greek Slave," a booklet entitled "Occasional Verses by Maunsell B. Field," and poems by Bayard Taylor, Thomas Ball, and Theodosia Trollope. Additional writings in this series include a brief account of Powers' studio by L. L. Barnes, a biographical account of Hiram Powers' life prior to moving to Europe in 1937, and a description of one of his sculptures by Frances Trollope. Other writings consist of a Phrenological study of Hiram Powers' personality, and two writings by unidentified authors which discuss Powers' artwork.
  This series has been divided into writings by Powers and writings by others. This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - Writings by Hiram Powers (Box 10)
    - "Studio Memorandum, Etc.,", 1841-1845 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - "Studio Memorandum, Etc.," Transcript, 1841-1845 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Poetry, circa mid-1800s (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Autobiographical Writings, circa 1827-1847 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Writing on Form and Color, circa mid-1800s (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Writings about Prejudice, circa mid-1800s (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - "A Ghost Story,", circa mid-1800s (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - "Directions to Young Sculptor,", circa mid-1800s (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Directions regarding Sculptures by Powers, circa 1849-1865 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, circa mid-1800s (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Writings by Others (Box 10)
    - Poetry, A-Z, 1837-1887; (Alphabetical by Author; 4 folders) (Box 10, Folder 36-39)
    - Poetry by Unidentified Authors, circa 1842-1847 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - L. L. Barnes, "Mr. Hiram Powers' Studio Florence,", 1865 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - L. N. Fowler, "Phrenological Description of Hiram Powers,", circa mid-1800s (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Lizzie Powers, "Life of H. P. 73,", circa 1873 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Frances Trollope, "A Story from Nature,", circa mid-1800s (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Unidentified Author, "Extracts from New Church Messenger,", 1885 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Unidentified Author, "Loose Notes on 'Fasces' in Literature and in Art,", 1859 (Box 10, Folder 46)
- Financial and Legal Records, circa 1840s-1892, 1915; Series 4; (Box 10, OV 17; 8 folders)
  This series contains scattered financial and legal records primarily documenting Hiram Powers' career as an artist. Included are patent documents for several sculpture designs, such as "Greek Slave," and for the invention of tools used in his studio. Also found are Power of Attorney agreements for Powers' business dealings in the United States while he lived in Florence, and other legal agreements, regarding both personal matters and the sale and commission of sculptures. This series also contains various financial account statements and miscellaneous financial records, such as bills and receipts. Many of these items are in Italian.
  Items are arranged chronologically within each folder. This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - Patent Documents, circa 1840s-1860; (See also OV 17) (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Power of Attorney Agreements, 1855-1872 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Hiram Powers Estate Documents, 1878-1892 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Legal Agreements and Contracts, 1843-1873, 1915; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 50-51)
  - Account and Loan Statements, 1845-1867 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Documents, circa 1852-1870 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Oversized Patent Document, 1855; (Scanned with Box 10, Folder 47) (Box OV 17)
- Printed Material, circa 1845-1953; Series 5; (Box 10; 5 folders)
  The small amount of printed material in this series includes two booklets, one belonging to Mrs. Powers and containing funeral addresses for the poet Bayard Taylor, and the other a collection of letters between the artist Miner Kellogg and his friends, including Hiram Powers. Also found is a catalog for an exhibition of Powers' sculpture and an art association brochure. News clippings document news of American artists in Florence, announcements regarding Powers' sculptures, news of Cincinnati, and news about Powers' friend, Frances Trollope.
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - Booklet, "Addresses Delivered at the Funeral of Bayard Taylor,", 1878 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Booklet, "Mr. Miner K. Kellogg to His Friends" (Reproduction), 1858 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Cincinnati Art Museum Exhibition Catalog, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - New Cosmopolitan Art and Literary Association Brochure, 1854 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Newspaper Clippings, circa 1845-1887, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 58)
- Photographs, circa 1860s-1900, 1927, 1932; Series 6; (Box 10-13, 16, OV 17; 1.8 linear feet)
  This series contains numerous photographs of Hiram Powers, his family, friends, notable public figures, and his artwork. Many of the photographs were taken by Hiram Powers' son, Longworth Powers who had a photograph studio in Florence. Found here are several portraits of Hiram Powers, including a portrait of him in his studio apron, standing next to a portrait bust, and photographs of him with the poet William Cullen Bryant and philanthropist George Peabody. Also found are portraits of his wife Elizabeth, son Preston, and three group photographs of the Powers family.
  Also within this series is Hiram Powers' extensive collection of 267 Cartes de Visite and Cabinet Cards depicting friends, notable figures, and those who sat for portraits by the artist, or who had portraits taken by Longworth Powers. Included are American and European artists, performers, politicians and other leaders, writers, and scientists, many of whom were friends with Powers. Notable figures include the artists Thomas Ball, Charles Francis Fuller, and John Everett Millais, performer Sarah Bernhardt, writers Robert Browning, Wilkie Collins, Horace Greeley, Victor Hugo, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, Bayard Taylor, John Ruskin, John Greenleaf Whittier, Alfred Tennyson, and Mark Twain, and others, such as William Lloyd Garrison, Henry Ward Beecher, Edward Everett, Florence Nightingale, David Livingston, Prince Napoleon, and Queen Victoria.
  Additional photographs contained in this series include five stereo cards of Woodstock, Vermont, including two photographs of the house where Hiram Powers was born, photographs of Italy and the marble quarry at Carrara, and a collection of photographs of Native Americans belonging to Preston Powers. Also found are photographs of artwork by Hiram and Preston Powers, including photographs of artwork in Powers' studio, and photographs of a painted portrait of a young Hiram Powers by Francis Alexander, and a second painted portrait by an unidentified artist.
  Also of note is a photograph album kept by Louisa Powers containing photographs of artwork by Powers and photographs of Italy, and two posters with attached photographs by Longworth Powers of people such as Hiram Powers, Thomas Ball, and their artwork, and photographs of Italy.
  This series also contains many glass plate photographs and negatives, including two lantern slides of unidentified people, possibly taken by Longworth Powers of members of the Powers family. Glass plate negatives consist of three portraits of Hiram Powers and one of his wife Elizabeth, other unidentified portraits, and photographs of sculpture by Powers, which can also be found among the printed photographs in this series.
  Photographs are arranged by format and subject matter. The bulk of this series has been scanned. Items not scanned include photographs and glass plate negatives of artwork. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
  - Photograph Portraits of Hiram Powers, circa 1860s-1870s; (2 folders; See also Box 16, Folder 1) (Box 10, Folder 59-60)
  - Photographs of Hiram Powers with William Cullen Bryant, circa 1865 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Photographs of Hiram Powers with George Peabody, circa 1860s (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Photograph of Hiram Powers Death Mask, circa 1888 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Photographs of Powers Family, circa 1860-1870 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Photographs of Hiram Powers Studio, circa 1860s; (See also Box 16, Folder 2) (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Cartes de Visite & Cabinet Cards (Box 10)
    - Artists, circa 1860s (Box 10, Folder 66)
    - Engineers & Industrialists, circa 1860s (Box 10, Folder 67)
    - English Nobility & Statesmen, circa 1860s-early 1870s (Box 10, Folder 68)
    - Military Leaders, circa 1860s-early 1870s (Box 10, Folder 69)
    - Performers, circa 1860s (Box 10, Folder 70)
    - Politicians, circa 1860s (Box 10, Folder 71)
    - Presidents, circa 1860s-early 1870s (Box 11 (hol), Folder 1)
    - Religious Leaders, circa 1860s-early 1870s (Box 11 (hol), Folder 2)
    - Royalty & International Politicians, circa 1860s-early 1870s (Box 11 (hol), Folder 3)
    - Scientists & Philosophers, circa 1860s-early 1870s (Box 11 (hol), Folder 4)
    - Writers & Poets, circa 1860s-early 1870s (Box 11 (hol), Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1860s-early 1870s (Box 11 (hol), Folder 6)
    - Unidentified People, circa 1860s-1870s (Box 11 (hol), Folder 7)
  - Photographs (Stereo Cards) of Woodstock, Vermont, 1874 (Box 11 (hol), Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Marble Quarry, Carrara, Italy, circa 1860s (Box 11 (hol), Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Italy, circa late-1800s (Box 11 (hol), Folder 10)
  - Photographs of Native Americans & Buffalo, circa 1880s (Box 11 (hol), Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Artwork by Hiram Powers, circa late-1800s; (2 folders; see also Box 16, Folder 3; not scanned) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 12-13)
  - Photographs of Sculpture by Preston Powers, circa 1870s; (Not scanned) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 14)
  - Photographs of Painted Portraits of Hiram Powers, circa late-1800s (Box 11 (hol), Folder 15)
  - Photographs of Artwork by Others, 1862, circa late-1800s; (Not scanned) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, circa 1860s-1880s, 1932; (See also Box 16, Folder 4) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 17)
  - Posters of Photographs by Longworth Powers, circa 1860s-late-1800s; (See OV 17) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 18)
  - Photograph Album belonging to Louisa Powers Ibbotson, 1927; (See Box 16) (Box 11 (hol), Folder 19)
  - Photographs under Glass, Sculpture, circa 1870s (Box 13)
    3 photographs under glass
  - Glass Plate Positives, Unidentified People, circa 1870s (Box 13)
    2 glass plate positives
  - Glass Plate Positives, Sculpture in Studio, circa 1870s (Box 13)
  - Lantern Slides, Sculpture, circa 1870s (Box 13)
    4 lantern slides
  - Glass Plate Negatives
    - Hiram Powers, circa 1870s (Box 12)
      1 glass plate negative